[{"Front":"Probability of wavefunction.","Back":"$|\\psi|^2 = \\psi^*\\psi$"},{"Front":"Time Independent Shrodinger Equation","Back":"$\\hat{H}\\psi=E\\psi$"},{"Front":"Born Approximation","Back":"$$f^{(1)}(\\vec{k},\\vec{k}') = -\\frac{1}{4\\pi}\\frac{2m}{\\hbar^2}\\int e^{-i(\\vec{k}'-\\vec{k})\\cdot \\vec x}V(\\vec{x})\\,d^3\\vec{x}$$"},{"Front":"Spherically Symmetric Born Approximation","Back":"$$f^{(1)}(\\theta) =-\\frac{2m}{\\hbar^2}\\frac{1}{q}\\int_0^\\infty rV(r)\\sin(qr)\\,dr,$$ where $q = 2k\\sin\\left(\\frac{\\theta}{2}\\right)$."},{"Front":"Yukawa Potential Scattering <br> $V(r) = V_0 \\frac{e^{-\\mu r}}{\\mu r}$.","Back":"$$f^{(1)}(\\theta) = \\left(\\frac{2mV_0}{\\mu h^2}\\right)\\frac{1}{q^2+\\mu^2}.$$"},{"Front":"Validity of Born Approximation","Back":"$$\\left|\\frac{2m}{\\hbar^2}\\frac{1}{4\\pi}\\int d^3 x'\\, \\frac{e^{ikr'}}{r'}V(\\vec{x}')e^{i\\vec{k}\\cdot \\vec{x}'}\\right| \\ll 1.$$"},{"Front":"Optical Theorem","Back":"$$\\sigma_{tot} = \\frac{4\\pi}{k}\\text{Im}[f(\\theta=0)]$$"},{"Front":"Partial Wave scattering amplitude","Back":"$$f(\\theta) = \\frac{1}{k}\\sum_l (2l+1)e^{i\\delta_l}\\sin\\delta_lP_l(\\cos\\theta)$$"},{"Front":"Partial Wave Total Cross Section","Back":"$$\\sigma_{tot} = \\frac{4\\pi}{k^2}\\sum_l(2l+1)\\sin^2\\delta_l.$$"},{"Front":"Asymtotic radial wave function for partial wave analysis","Back":"$$A_l(r) = e^{i\\delta_l}[\\cos\\delta_l j_l(kr) - \\sin\\delta_ln_l(kr)].$$"},{"Front":"Scattering Length","Back":"$$-\\frac{1}{a} = \\lim_{k\\to 0}k\\cot\\delta_0$$ <br> where $a$ is the scattering length."},{"Front":"Non-Degenerate Time-Independent first order energy shift and correction.","Back":"$$\\Delta_n^{(1)} = \\langle n^{(0)}|V|n^{(0)}\\rangle$$ $$|n^{(1)}\\rangle = \\sum_{k\\neq n} \\frac{\\langle k^{(0)}|V|n^{(0)}\\rangle}{E_n^{(0)}-E_k^{(0)}}|k^{(0)}\\rangle$$  where $V$ is pertubation."},{"Front":"Non-Degenerate Time-Independent second order energy shift","Back":"$$\\Delta_n^{(2)} = \\sum_{k\\neq n} \\frac{|\\langle k^{(0)}|V|n^{(0)}\\rangle|^2}{E_n^{(0)}-E_k^{(0)}}$$ <br> where $V$ is pertubation."},{"Front":"Wavefunction probability current","Back":"$$\\vec{j} = \\frac{-i\\hbar}{2m}(\\psi^*\\nabla\\psi - \\psi \\nabla \\psi^*)$$"},{"Front":"Fourier Transform of particle in 3D","Back":"$$\\phi(\\vec{p}) = \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{2\\pi\\hbar}}\\int d^3\\vec{r}\\,e^{-i\\vec{p}\\cdot \\vec{r}/\\hbar}\\psi(\\vec{r})$$  $$\\psi(\\vec{r}) = \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{2\\pi\\hbar}}\\int d^3\\vec{p}\\, e^{i\\vec{p}\\cdot \\vec{r}/\\hbar}\\phi(\\vec{p})$$"},{"Front":"Time-dependent Shrodinger Equation","Back":"$i\\hbar \\frac{\\partial}{\\partial t}\\psi = \\hat{H}\\psi$"},{"Front":"Heisenberg Equation","Back":"$$\\frac{d}{dt}\\hat{A}(t) = \\frac{i}{\\hbar}[\\hat{H},\\hat{A}(t)]+\\frac{\\partial \\hat{A}(t)}{\\partial t}$$."},{"Front":"Time evolution of operator expectation in Heisenberg picture","Back":"$\\frac{d}{dt}\\langle \\hat{A}\\rangle = \\frac{1}{i\\hbar}\\langle [\\hat{A},\\hat{H}]\\rangle+\\left\\langle \\frac{\\partial \\hat A}{\\partial t}\\right\\rangle.$"},{"Front":"Single Particle Hamiltonian","Back":"$\\hat{H} = \\frac{\\hat{p}^2}{2m}+V(\\vec{x}) = -\\frac{\\hbar^2}{2m}\\nabla^2+V(\\vec{x})$."},{"Front":"1-D momentum operator in position basis","Back":"$\\hat{p} = -i\\hbar \\frac{d}{dx}$"},{"Front":"De Broglie relation","Back":"$p=\\frac{hf}{c} = \\frac{h}{\\lambda}$."},{"Front":"Heisenberg Uncertainty relationship","Back":"$\\sigma(A)\\sigma(B) \\geq \\frac{1}{2}\\langle i[\\hat{A},\\hat{B}]\\rangle.$"},{"Front":"Variance calculation (Dispersion)","Back":"$\\sigma(A)^2 = \\langle A^2\\rangle - \\langle A \\rangle^2.$"},{"Front":"Density of states in 1d,2d,3d of particle in a box","Back":"3D-$g(E)=\\frac{8\\pi\\sqrt{2}}{h^3}m^{3/2}\\sqrt{E}$<br>2D-$g(E) =\\frac{2\\pi m a^2}{h^2}$, where $a$ is dimension. <br> 1D-$g(E)=\\frac{a\\sqrt{8m}}{2h\\sqrt{E}}$."},{"Front":"Fermi-Dirac Distribution (fermions)","Back":"$P(E_i) = \\frac{g(E_i)}{e^{\\beta(E-\\mu)}+1}$<br> $\\beta = 1/k_BT$."},{"Front":"Bose-Einstein Distribution (bosons)","Back":"$P(E_i) = \\frac{g(E_i)}{e^{\\beta(E-\\mu)}-1}$<br> $\\beta = 1/k_BT$."},{"Front":"Magnitude of angular momentum operator $\\hat{J}$.","Back":"$|\\hat{J}| = \\hbar\\sqrt{j(j+1)}$."},{"Front":"Angular momentum eigenvalue $J_z$","Back":"$J_z | j,m_j\\rangle = m_j\\hbar |j,m_j\\rangle$."},{"Front":"Angular momentum eigenvalue $J^2$","Back":"$J^2| j,m_j\\rangle = \\hbar^2j(j+1) | j,m_j\\rangle$."},{"Front":"Energy levels of hydrogen atom","Back":"$E_n = -\\frac{me^4}{8\\epsilon_0h^2n^2}= -\\frac{13.61eV}{n^2}$."},{"Front":"Angular momentum commutation relations","Back":"$$[L_l,L_m]=i\\hbar \\sum_{n=1}^3 \\epsilon_{lmn}L_n$$ <br> ex. $[L_x,L_y] =i\\hbar L_z$."},{"Front":"$[L^2,L_i]$ where $i=x,y,z$.","Back":"$0$."},{"Front":"Ladder operators","Back":"$$J_+ = J_x + iJ_y$$ $$J_- = J_x - iJ_y$$."},{"Front":"${n \\choose k}$","Back":"$$\\frac{n!}{k!(n-k)!}$$"},{"Front":"Stirling's Apprximation","Back":"$$\\ln(n!) = n\\ln(n)-n$$"},{"Front":"Microcanonical Entropy","Back":"$$S = k_B \\ln \\Omega,$$ <br> where $\\Omega$ is number of microstates."},{"Front":"Zeroth law of Thermodynamics","Back":"If systems A and B are in thermal equilibrium and systems B and C are in thermal equilibrium, then systems A and C are in thermal equilibrium."},{"Front":"First Law of Thermodynamics","Back":"$$\\Delta U = Q - W,$$ where $Q$ is the heat supplied to the system and $W$ is the work done by the system on its surroundings."},{"Front":"Change in internal energy for quasi-static process","Back":"$$dU = \\delta Q - PdV$$"},{"Front":"Second Law of Thermodynamics","Back":"$$dS = \\frac{dQ}{T}$$, where $dQ$ is an inexact differential."},{"Front":"Gaussian Integral","Back":"$$\\int_{-\\infty}^\\infty e^{-a(x+b)^2}\\,dx = \\sqrt{\\frac{\\pi}{a}}.$$"},{"Front":"Geometric Series","Back":"$$\\sum_{k=0}^\\infty r^k = \\frac{1}{1-r}$$ <br> if $|r| < 1$."},{"Front":"Fermi Golden Rule","Back":"$$P(i\\to f) = \\frac{2\\pi}{\\hbar}|\\langle f|V|i\\rangle|^2\\delta(E_f-E_i)$$"},{"Front":"Perturbation Therory sudden approximation","Back":"State doesn't change, is now a linear combination of perturbed eigenstates.  Time dependance is based on evolution under new Hamiltonian."},{"Front":"One electron Hamiltonian in atomic units","Back":"$$h(1) = -\\frac{1}{2}\\nabla^2_1-\\frac{Z}{r_1}$$"},{"Front":"$$\\langle 1s_\\zeta|h|1s_\\zeta\\rangle$$ where $h$ is the one electron Hailtonian and $\\zeta$ is a screeing constant in terms of $Z$, the atomic number in atomic units.","Back":"$$-Z\\zeta +\\frac{\\zeta^2}{2}$$"},{"Front":"$$[1s^2|1s^2] = \\iint 1s(1)^2\\frac{1}{r_{12}}1s(2)^2dV_1dV_2$$","Back":"$$\\frac{5\\zeta}{8}$$"},{"Front":"Angular momentum raising and lowering operator","Back":"$$J_\\pm|j,m\\rangle = \\hbar\\sqrt{j(j+1)-m(m\\pm 1)}|j,m\\rangle.$$"},{"Front":"Creation and annhiliation operator in terms of position and momentum","Back":"$$\\hat{a}^\\dagger = \\sqrt{\\frac{m\\omega}{2\\hbar}}\\left(\\hat{x}-\\frac{i}{m\\omega}\\hat{p}\\right).$$ $$\\hat{a} = \\sqrt{\\frac{m\\omega}{2\\hbar}}\\left(\\hat{x}+\\frac{i}{m\\omega}\\hat{p}\\right).$$"},{"Front":"Equations of creation and annhiliation operators on number states","Back":"$$\\hat{a}|n\\rangle = \\sqrt{n}|n-1\\rangle$$ $$\\hat{a}^\\dagger|n\\rangle = \\sqrt{n+1}|n+1\\rangle $$"},{"Front":"Fundamental Relation (E,S,V,N)","Back":"$$dE = TdS - pdV + \\mu dN$$"},{"Front":"Gibbs-Duhem relation","Back":"$$SdT - Vdp + N d\\mu =0$$"},{"Front":"Given $df = adx + dy$, where $a = (\\partial f/\\partial x)_y$ and $b=(\\partial f/\\partial y)_x,$ relate partials of $a$ and $b$.","Back":"$$\\left(\\frac{\\partial a}{\\partial y}\\right)_x = \\left(\\frac{\\partial b}{\\partial x}\\right)_y,$$ since they both equal $\\frac{\\partial^2 f}{\\partial x \\partial y}$."},{"Front":"Consider a function $z(x,y)$, triple rule relating partial derivatives.","Back":"$$\\left(\\frac{\\partial x}{\\partial y}\\right)_z \\cdot\\left(\\frac{\\partial y}{\\partial z}\\right)_x\\cdot\\left(\\frac{\\partial z}{\\partial x}\\right)_y=-1.$$"},{"Front":"Relationship between chemical potential and Gibb's free energy","Back":"$$G = \\mu N$$, so chemical potential is Gibb's free energy per partical, and $\\mu = \\left(\\frac{\\partial G}{\\partial N}\\right)_{T,p}$ as well."},{"Front":"Helmholtz free energy differential relation","Back":"$$dA = -SdT - pdV + \\mu dN$$"},{"Front":"Enthalpy differential relation","Back":"$$dH = TdS + Vdp + \\mu dN$$"},{"Front":"Gibbs Free Energy Differential relation","Back":"$$dG = -SdT + Vdp + \\mu dN$$"},{"Front":"Entropy of ideal gas (Sakur-Tetrode equation)","Back":"$$S = k_B \\left[\\ln\\left(\\frac{V}{N}\\left(\\frac{4\\pi m E}{3Nh^2}\\right)^{3/2}\\right)+\\frac{5}{2}\\right].$$"},{"Front":"Poisson distribution","Back":"$$Pr(X=k)=\\frac{1}{k!}\\lambda^k e^{-\\lambda}.$$"},{"Front":"Mean and Variance of Poisson Distribution $$Pr(X=k)=\\frac{1}{k!}\\lambda^k e^{-\\lambda}.$$","Back":"Mean and Variance both $\\lambda$."},{"Front":"Ideal Gas Partition Function","Back":"$$Z = \\frac{V^N}{N!}\\left(\\frac{2\\pi m k_B T}{h^2}\\right)^{3N/2}$$"},{"Front":"$L_z$ in angular coordinates.","Back":"$$L_z = -i\\hbar \\frac{\\partial }{\\partial \\phi}$$"},{"Front":"$x,y,z$ in polar coordinates","Back":"$$x = r\\sin\\theta\\cos\\phi$$ $$y=r\\sin\\theta\\sin\\phi$$ $$z=r\\cos\\theta$$"},{"Front":"3D harmonic oscillator energies in radial coordinates","Back":"$$E_{n,l} = \\hbar\\omega\\left(2n+l + \\frac{3}{2}\\right)$$"},{"Front":"Critical point equation","Back":"$$\\left(\\frac{\\partial p}{\\partial V}\\right)_T = \\left(\\frac{\\partial^2 p}{\\partial V^2}\\right)_T=0$$"},{"Front":"Radial Shrodinger Equation","Back":"$$\\left\\{-\\frac{\\hbar^2}{2mr^2}\\frac{d}{dr}\\left(r^2\\frac{d}{dr}\\right)+\\frac{\\hbar^2l(l+1)}{2mr^2}+V(r)\\right\\}R(r) = ER(r)$$"},{"Front":"$x,y,z$ in spherical coordinates","Back":"$$x = r\\sin\\theta\\cos\\phi$$ $$y = r\\sin\\theta\\sin\\phi$$ $$z = r\\cos\\theta$$"},{"Front":"Heat capcity in terms of $\\beta$","Back":"$$C_v = -k_B \\beta^2\\left(\\frac{\\partial E}{\\partial \\beta}\\right)_V.$$"},{"Front":"Wigner-Eckart Theorem","Back":"$$\\langle \\gamma'j'm'|T^k_q|\\gamma j m\\rangle = \\langle\\gamma'j'||T^k||\\gamma j\\rangle\\langle j'm'|jkmq\\rangle.$$"},{"Front":"General energy density of states","Back":"$$\\rho^{(d)}(\\epsilon) = \\Omega_d\\left(\\frac{L}{2\\pi}\\right)^d\\frac{1}{2}\\left(\\frac{2m}{\\hbar^2}\\right)^{d/2}\\epsilon^{d/2-1}$$ where $\\Omega_D = \\begin{cases} 4\\pi &d=3\\\\ 2\\pi&d=2\\\\1&d=1\\end{cases}$"},{"Front":"Isothermal compressability","Back":"$$\\xi_T = -\\frac{1}{V}\\left(\\frac{\\partial V}{\\partial P}\\right)_T > 0$$"},{"Front":"Electromagnetic Hamiltonian","Back":"$$H = \\frac{1}{2m}\\left(p-\\frac{e}{c}\\vec{A}\\right)^2+V_c(r)$$  $\\vec{E}=-\\frac{1}{c}\\frac{\\partial \\vec{A}}{\\partial t}$, $\\vec{B} = \\nabla\\times\\vec{A}$."},{"Front":"Fermi Golden Rule for emmission/absorbtion","Back":"$$\\omega_{i\\to n} = \\frac{2\\pi e^2}{\\hbar m^2 c^2}A_0^2\\left|\\left\\langle n \\left|\\vec{p}\\cdot \\hat{\\epsilon}e^{i\\vec{k}\\cdot \\vec{r}}\\right|i\\right\\rangle\\right|^2\\delta(E_n-E_i\\pm\\hbar\\omega),$$ where $\\vec{A}=2A_0\\hat{\\epsilon}\\cos(\\vec{k}\\cdot\\vec{r}-\\omega t)$."},{"Front":"Solution to Rabi problem with oscillation of strength $\\delta$ and frequency $\\omega$ starting in state $1$.","Back":"$$|c_2(t)|=\\frac{\\delta^2}{\\delta^2+\\hbar^2(\\omega-\\omega_{21})/4}\\sin^2\\Omega t$$ where $$\\Omega = \\sqrt{\\left(\\frac{\\delta}{\\hbar}\\right)^2+(\\omega-\\omega_{21})/4}.$$"},{"Front":"First order time dependant pertubation coefficient","Back":"$$c_n^{(1)}(t) = -\\frac{i}{\\hbar}\\int_0^t dt'\\, e^{i\\omega_{ni}t'}\\langle n|V|i\\rangle,$$ where $V$ is the perturbation in the interaction picture and $\\omega_{ni} = (E_n-E_i)/\\hbar$."},{"Front":"Baker-Campbell-Hausdorff identity","Back":"$$e^{\\hat A}\\hat{B}e^{-\\hat{A}} = \\hat{B} + [\\hat{A},\\hat{B}]+\\frac{1}{2!}[\\hat{A},[\\hat{A},\\hat{B}]]+\\dots$$"},{"Front":"$$\\int_0^\\infty x^n e^{-\\alpha x}\\,dx$$ where $\\alpha >0$","Back":"$$\\int_0^\\infty x^n e^{-\\alpha x}\\,dx=\\frac{n!}{\\alpha^{n+1}}.$$"},{"Front":"Thermal WaveLength","Back":"$$\\lambda_T = \\sqrt{\\frac{h^2}{2\\pi m k_B T}}$$"},{"Front":"Concavity and Convexity of Thermodynamics Potentials","Back":"For constant $N$, the thermodynamic potentials (energy and its Legendre transforms) are convex functions of their extensive varialbes and concave functions of their intensive variabls.  For constant $N$ entropy and its Legendre transforms are concave functions of their extensive variables and convex functions of their intensive variables."}]